Here, we have an object called cat as well as a function, sayHello.
هنا، لدينا كائنًا يُسمى "cat" إضافة إلى دالة "sayHello".
All sayHello does is taking a single parameter and prints out a message to the console.
وكل ما تفعله "sayHello" هو أخذ معلمة وحيدة وتقوم بطباعة رسالة إلى وحدة التحكم.
Now, this might look kind of peculiar,
الآن، قد يبدو ذلك غريبًا،
because sayHello actually references the "this" keyword.
نظرًا لأن "sayHello" تُشير بالفعل إلى الكلمة الأساسية "this".
If we invoked sayHello as a function,
إذا استدعينا "sayHello" باعتبارها دالة،
what would "this" get set to?
فما الذي ستقوم "this" بتعيينه؟
Well, it would get set to window or the global object.
حسنًا، إنها ستقوم بتعيين نافذة أو كائن عام.
So, if you wanted "this" to refer to cat,
لذلك، إذا أردتم أن تُشير "this" إلى "cat"،
we can do it ourselves manually using the special call or apply methods.
فيمكننا فعلها بأنفسنا يدويًا باستخدام استدعاء خاص أو أساليب "apply".
Let's check out how we can do that, starting with call.
دعونا نتحقق من كيفية فعلنا لها، بالبدء باستخدام استدعاء.
Call's a method that we can invoke directly onto a function. Let's go ahead and do that.
أسلوب "Call" الذي يمكننا استدعائه مباشرة إلى الدالة. لنتابع ونفعل هذا.
We can pass in two arguments right now into the call method.
يمكننا تمرير وسيطتين الآن إلى أسلوب "Call".
First, it'll be the object that we bind "this" to which will be cat.
أولًا، سوف يكون الكائن الذي نربط "this"بما سيكون "cat".
Next, it's a set of arguments passed into the function that call is being called on,
وبعد ذلك، إنها مجموعة من الوسيطات التي يتم تمريرها إلى الدالة التي يتم استدعاء "call" بها،
in this case would be Hello,
وفي هذه الحالة ستكون "Hello"،
and we know that it takes in a single argument. Just message.
ونعلم أنها تتضمن وسيطة واحدة. مجرد رسالة.
Let's go ahead and pass on that message.
لنتابع ونقوم بتمرير تلك الرسالة.
Great, let's go ahead and execute this and see what we get.
رائع، لنتابع ونعمل على تنفيذ ذلك ونرى ما نحصل عليه.
And there you have it. Nice to see you, Bailey.
وهي لديكم الآن. "Nice to see you, Bailey.&lrm;"
We can actually achieve the same results using the apply method,
يمكننا تحقيقُ النتائج نفسها حقًا باستخدام أسلوب "apply"،
but the arguments passed on are a little bit different.
لكن الوسيطات التي يتم تمريرها مختلفة قليلًا.
Let's check it out. I'll switch to
لنراجع هذا. سأنتقل الآن إلى
the other window right now to give myself a little bit more space here.
النافذة الأخرى لأوفر لنفسي بعض المساحة هنا.
Just like call, apply is directly invoked onto a function.
تمامًا مثل "call"، يتم استدعاء "apply" مباشرةً إلى الدلة.
The first argument should be the same,
يجب أن تكون الوسيطة الأولى متماثلة،
which is just the object that you want to bind this to, in this case would be cat.
وما هي إلا الكائن الذي تريدون ربط هذا به، في هذه الحالة سيكون "cat".
Next, rather than separating individual arguments that will be passed
وبعد ذلك، فبدلًا من فصل الوسيطات الفردية التي سيتم تمريرها
into the sayHello function by commas like we do with call,
إلى الدالة "sayHello" باستخدام الفواصل مثلما نفعل مع "call"،
apply actually takes in all the arguments in the form of an array.
يتضمن "apply" بالفعل كافة الوسيطات في شكل مصفوفة.
Again, we know in this case it's a single argument
مرة أخرى، نعلم في هذه الحالة أنها وسيطة واحدة
because sayHello only takes in message.
نظرًا لأن "sayHello" تتضمن رسالة فحسب.
So let's go ahead and pass on our message in an array.
لنتابع ونقوم بتمرير رسالتنا في مصفوفة.
Great, let's invoke it and see what happens.
رائع، لنقوم باستدعائها ونرى ما سيحدث.
Hello, Bailey. There we go.
"Hello, Bailey.&lrm;" هيا نواصل.
Call and apply are great ways to set the value of "this" ourselves.
يعد كل من "Call" و"apply" طريقتين رائعتين لتعيين قيمة "this" بأنفسنا.